<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title type="text" xml:lang="en">Jarrah Technology</title>
    <link type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link type="text" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com" rel="alternate"/>
    <updated>2022-10-03T16:15:46+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com</id>
    <author>
        <name>Jarrah Technology</name>
    </author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2012 Jarrah Technology</rights>

    
    <entry>
        <title>Need For Speed - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/10/03/Need-For-Speed.html/"/>
        <published>2022-10-03T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2022-10-03T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/10/03/Need-For-Speed.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you looked at SHD a month ago and again today, you would probably notice no difference at all. However, behind the scenes a great deal has changed. Over the last month my main task has been improving the AI. It soon became clear a major issue was speed. Examining a set of moves took several milliseconds (ms), and there were often thousands of possible moves, sometimes tens of thousands - it was taking too long. In speeding up the analysis, errors began creeping into the system caused by timing and threading issues. Hmmm. I decided to change the way the engine worked so that these errors could not occur and managed to get this largely complete in a week. The result was that average analysis time for a single set of moves went from 5ms to 0.19ms, error free. Proud of that work. It  should be fast enough to let the AI to look more than one move ahead - which is the next task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got a little distracted by possible future projects. Now have another good idea for the next project. Hard decisions will need to be made soon around what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SHD tasks for November are the same as before, just the AI is now very close to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month’s completed tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moved SHD engine from a Plan/Action pattern to a Command/Effect pattern&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AI working well, just speeding up code so that can process more scenarios in reasonable time (5ms to 0.19ms so far)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Played with setups &amp;amp; org for next project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bugfixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full AI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little improvements &amp;amp; bugfixes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next version of prototypes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Online component&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try not to get distracted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Light At The End Of The Tunnel - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/09/01/Light-Tunnel.html/"/>
        <published>2022-09-01T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2022-09-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/09/01/Light-Tunnel.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The point has been reached where the end is so near, I find my attention waning and drifting to other projects. This month I spent nearly a record low number of hours on SHD, and yet my todo list is still quite short. Today I went through the list of ideas/issues/features remaining. Most are not worth doing, or are code improvements for the next game (they will make no significant difference to this one). The ones left I grouped by theme and numbered by importance - the last is #5. The first is the long-planned full AI; second is the online componenent. The others are not worth mentioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what did I do this past month? The first couple of weeks was spent finishing off the r/roguelikedev tutorial event &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/08/17/Roguelike.html&quot;&gt;(see this post for more info)&lt;/a&gt;. Then I spent some (too much!) time moving all my websites from &lt;a href=&quot;www.linode.com&quot;&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;www.github.com&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. Not because I’m unhappy with Linode (they have been great), but to same time by not managing my own virtual servers for a couple of simple static websites. Then I did a little daydreaming of ideas. Lastly a few hours fixing up bugs, tooltips and unlocks before starting work on the AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SHD tasks for the coming month are to just finish the damn thing (maybe not this month, but hopefully next).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month’s completed tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little improvements &amp;amp; bugfixes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move websites/repos to free hosts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;r/roguelikedev tutorial event complete &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/08/17/Roguelike.html&quot;&gt;(see this post to play)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multi-frame AI framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full AI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little improvements &amp;amp; bugfixes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next version of prototypes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Online component&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try not to get distracted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Roguelike Tutorial 2022</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/08/17/Roguelike.html/"/>
        <published>2022-08-17T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-17T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/08/17/Roguelike.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As a distraction from other things I should have been doing over the last 6 weeks, I completed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/roguelikedev/comments/vhfsda/roguelikedev_does_the_complete_roguelike_tutorial/&quot;&gt;/r/roguelikedev Tutorial 2022&lt;/a&gt;. An event to teach people how to write roguelike games like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NetHack&quot;&gt;Nethack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Angband_%28video_game%29&quot;&gt;Angband&lt;/a&gt;, and my old favourite, &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2016/07/omega.html&quot;&gt;Omega&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to learn some &lt;a href=&quot;https://javascript.info/&quot;&gt;Javascript&lt;/a&gt;, and this seemed a good way to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is done now. There is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jarrahtech.github.io/RoguelikeTutorial2022/&quot;&gt;playable version here&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jarrahtech/RoguelikeTutorial2022&quot;&gt;source code is here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The controls are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;movement/target: arrow keys or wasd (+qezx)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;look: ‘/’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pickup: ‘p’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;message history: ‘v’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;drop/leave: ‘l’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;activate/use/equip: ‘u’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;character screen: ‘c’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/jarrahtech/RoguelikeTutorial2022/blob/main/assets/img/logo.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;/r/roguelikedev Tutorial2022 Logo&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Joining The Club - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/08/01/Joining-The-Club.html/"/>
        <published>2022-08-01T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/08/01/Joining-The-Club.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In July I joined the club - the Covid19 club. Luckily it was a fairly mild case but it still stopped work for nearly a fortnight (2 days in bed, a few days feeling sick and then a week super-tired). As a result I did very few hours on SHD, especially since the few hours I did spend coding were for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://old.reddit.com/r/roguelikedev/comments/vhfsda/roguelikedev_does_the_complete_roguelike_tutorial/&quot;&gt;/r/roguelikedev annual tutorial event&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jarrahtech/RoguelikeTutorial2022&quot;&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://jarrahtech.github.io/RoguelikeTutorial2022/&quot;&gt;playable version&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So achievements are light this months. I have completed weeks 2 through 5 in the /r/roguelikedev challenge, with only 3 more weeks left. It has been worth doing (learning Javascript can only be useful) and without the structure I doubt I would have bothered. Given me a few more ideas to add to the list. As for SHD, I added and hooked up all the remaining planned unlocks/achievements. Plus a few bugfixes, that is it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SHD tasks for the coming month are the same as last month: AI and cleanup. I’ll hopefully also get to move the websites, and of course, the last 3 weeks of the r/roguelikedev event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month’s completed tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wk 2-5 /r/roguelikedev tutorial event&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All unlocks/achievements done&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some bugfixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full AI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little improvements &amp;amp; bugfixes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next version of prototypes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move websites/repos to free hosts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Online component&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;complete r/roguelikedev tutorial event&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Holiday - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/07/01/Holiday.html/"/>
        <published>2022-07-01T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2022-07-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/07/01/Holiday.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As expected June was a truncated month. A weeks holiday interstate and a couple of days dealing with house issues (the joys of living in an old house) put a big hole in my productivity and definitely slowed progress as I lost momentum. Maybe that is what has lead to me deciding to join the &lt;a href=&quot;https://old.reddit.com/r/roguelikedev/comments/vhfsda/roguelikedev_does_the_complete_roguelike_tutorial/&quot;&gt;/r/roguelikedev annual tutorial event&lt;/a&gt;. “Wait,” you say, “don’t you need to finish SHD first before starting another game?” Yes, you are right. This is almost certainly a bad use of my time, especially since I am trying it in a Javascript, a language I haven’t used properly in over 20 years (also, trying to relearn Git &amp;amp; Github at the same time). However, I think it might be useful for future work and I hope to spend no more than one day per week on getting it going (Week 1 took 2 hours, so far so good). If you want to see the WIP, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jarrahtech/RoguelikeTutorial2022&quot;&gt;repo is here&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jarrahtech.github.io/RoguelikeTutorial2022/&quot;&gt;playable version here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SHD is still getting very close to the end now too (about time!). I have added a bunch of new gameplay mechanics: base recharging; base powerups; and bombs. Last time I said the game quickly devolved into a slow defensive slog. Now, not so much. It is not a great game, although definitely a little better than before - and importantly, shorter! There was also some visual improvements and work on achievements. Not the best month in terms of hours worked, but there is clear progress. It was gratifying to see how easily the new mechancis were added due to the earlier framework tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remaining SHD tasks are now AI and cleanup. That is the plan for the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month’s completed tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wk 1 /r/roguelikedev tutorial event&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reorganised achievements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little visual improvements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reworked gameplay to make game faster more interesting - recharge, powerup bases, bomb hex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finalise unlocks/achievements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full AI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little improvements &amp;amp; bugfixes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next version of prototypes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move websites/repos to free hosts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Online component&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;r/roguelikedev tutorial event&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Done? - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/06/01/Done.html/"/>
        <published>2022-06-01T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2022-06-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/06/01/Done.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;May was a solid month of work. Could have bee a record if not for losing 4 complete days to sickness and probably lower productivity for a few days after. There is a new AI and lots of little improvements. If a player want to keep going forever there is also now an “infinite” mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest task completed was the engine rework - now finished and all (known) resulting bugs cleared. It took 6 weeks total. I thought in the best case it would require nearly 2 weeks, but gave myself 4 weeks due to experience :) So 6 weeks is not great, but not bad. Of course not all the time was taken with refactoring, there was also some prototype and time and a jaunt into the land of node servers and docker (just to learn about them) along the way, but that sort of thing is expected. Still think it was worth it, the final code is much better and more flexible! I’m happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;June will be a short month (I’m away for a week), so of course I have a totally unrealistic list of tasks. The big one is to improve the gameplay. Playing against the new AI quickly results in a defensive slog of a game - not what I had intended. Hopefully I can think of some ways to improve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month’s completed tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rework engine complete&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New AI - but now game bogs down into defensive slogs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Infinite mode&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little visual improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve gameplay?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rearrange unlocks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full AI (current version does not take advantage of all gameplay possibilities)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next version of prototypes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move websites/repos to free hosts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look at online component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Refactoring - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/05/02/Refactoring.html/"/>
        <published>2022-05-02T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2022-05-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/05/02/Refactoring.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;April was a month of steady progress. I managed to get 3 games of the IPO prototype played and one of the Ci2d prototype. All went surprisingly well considering expectations. In particular the Ci2d prototype was not completely broken, it played (as intended) like a simplified version of the original - definitely will put some more work into a v2. The mechanics of IPO are fairly steady now. The game drags a little in the mid-game, but that is because I removed some of the more interactive cards (I hope). Now I will try to derive a formula for card strength and add back the interesting cards so combos can be built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rework of SHD’s engine is continuing. It works and is so pretty. Now it just needs to be fully implemented and the old code removed. Hopefully that will complete be before the end of this month. Strangely the new system went through a few design changes to handle cases I didn’t initially consider, and now it looks a lot like the engine in CI (just more abstract). Hmmmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month’s completed tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Played IPO v4 prototype x3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Played Ci2D v1 prototype x1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rework engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish work to improve and componentise/abstract the action system, plus AI (basically build a reusable simulation engine as a backend component)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fix infinite mode, separate  random mode, and rearrange unlocks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better AI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Play new prototypes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Sticking Point? - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/04/05/Sticking-Point.html/"/>
        <published>2022-04-05T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2022-04-05T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/04/05/Sticking-Point.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have now reached the same point in SHD where I stopped AHB (the “prototype” that went too far). When I decided to stop and restart, I estimated that the work required to fix the problems would take weeks and not be worth the effort. I think the same work will take a week or two with SHD - much better. Also, once done it should be reusable for other turn-based gamedev. Of course I reached that point less half way through the last month, so why isn’t it finished? Well, I haven’t started yet. Instead those distractions (household work and a one week holiday) I mentioned last month took focus. Knowing this was going to happen I worked on tabletop prototypes and little tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month’s completed tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IPO v4 prototype (unplayed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ci2D v1 prototype (unplayed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Level loading system &amp;amp; screen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simple AI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio setup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve and componentise/abstract the action system and AI (basically build a reusable simulation engine as a backend component)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fix infinite mode, separate  random mode, and rearrange unlocks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better AI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Play new prototypes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Short Month, Record Hours - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/03/01/Short-Month-Record-Hours.html/"/>
        <published>2022-03-01T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2022-03-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/03/01/Short-Month-Record-Hours.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Despite being the shortest month of the year, the February was my best for hours worked. Mainly due to one week being almost full-time on the game - the benefit of it being too hot to be outside (ahh, I love my A/C). I’m not going to publicise the hours I worked - it is still well below my (already low) target. However, in the last report I wrote that I hoped to complete: targetting, shooting, extra actions, handle the end of a game, and unlocks. I did all of that and more: context sensitive tooltips and some framework niceties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this month is not expected to be as productive. There are several house related tasks that got paused waiting for more inclement temperatures - and today the weather turned! Despite this I expect good progress as the biggest task remaining is the AI, and after no further significant functionality is planned (online multiplayer would be such an item, but I’d want to have a version on stores before starting that). Instead, it is all things to make the game prettier and nicer. Thus, I have added a couple of new tasks to the possibles for the month - new prototypes and some library work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work on SHD (play screen, AI, playability improvements)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create IPO prototype version 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decide which projects to pursue immediately, and which to put on pause.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First paper prototypes for the next 1 or 2 games&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common library work (card and backporting SHD stuff)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Moving Again? - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/02/02/Moving-Again.html/"/>
        <published>2022-02-02T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2022-02-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/02/02/Moving-Again.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Before compiling the results for January, I was a little disappointed in myself. I remember it taking a couple of weeks to get moving as other home tasks took precedence. However, after going through my notes, the result looks more like a normal month - a couple of better than average weeks after a couple of worse than average weeks. Consistency is my problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is coming along nicely. The UI is complete and working well (apart from tooltips, to be done later). Forming and moving bases is complete; targeting and firing is in progress. Everything so far works better than before. Perhaps the second time I know better what is required - a point of evidence in favour of prototypes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another two entries have been added onto the game ideas list - time to start culling it. I have also bought some tabletop components as I have plans to create tabletop prototypes of my next games - it is such a great way of iterating through designs quickly. With these new components I will be able to prototype Ci2d, plus a couple of others. I just need a week or so to come up with a set of starting rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work on SHD (targetting, shooting, extra action, end of game &amp;amp; unlocks)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create IPO prototype version 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decide which projects to pursue immediately, and which to put on pause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Standstill - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/01/02/Standstill.html/"/>
        <published>2022-01-02T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2022-01-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/01/02/Standstill.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we ring in the new year, it occurred to me that my current game is about at the same playable state as this time last year. Hmmmm.
Of course, I now have a reusable library (hopefully, the test will be in the reuse) and the code is much nicer. However, it seems
as bit poor to make no progress on the ultimate measure of a game - its playability and fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last month the game has become playable again. The turn structure is in and stamps complete. I’ve have also replaced the
health/strength/time displays with shader based radial sprites, rather than the weird looking 3D line drawings in a 2D world. Work has now started on the player UI - my worst gamedev skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been no work on IPO, but I am getting more ideas for various games. I need to get this one finished before my interest wanes, as I feel it doing. I started December with a rush, but that slowed greatly over the fortnight for Christmas and New Years. I need to get back that previous productivity. Time sinks over the next month include a ton of house issues (old houses!), but thanks to the current pandemic lockdown and heatwave, exercise time is minimal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work on SHD (get UI working)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create IPO prototype version 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decide which projects to pursue immediately, and which to put on pause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Housework - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/12/06/Housework.html/"/>
        <published>2021-12-06T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2021-12-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/12/06/Housework.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Did you notice I missed a month? October started well with work on cleaning up the display before adding drag and drop (the main game mechanism).
There was also some work to improve the config options and putting the source repo on a remote server so I can work anywhere with Internet (not just on my home PC).
Then by the end of that month everything stopped, and stayed stopped through November.
There are now three people living in this house and it took some time cleaning up and fixing various things in readiness for their arrival.
Followed by more tasks as they settled in.
Hopefully all that is finished now (apart from this Wednesday afternoon) and I can get back to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month (same as last time):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work on SHD (and have basic play possible)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create IPO prototype version 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decide which projects to pursue immediately, and which to put on pause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Distractions - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/10/03/Distractions.html/"/>
        <published>2021-10-03T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2021-10-03T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/10/03/Distractions.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;September was a month of distractions. Work continued on SHB, but at a slow pace. A significant amount of time was also spent trying out the new Scala3 and I converted the hex library into that language - it works well (now I’m thinking about SAAS projects again). Outside of work stress and tasks is still high. Unfortunately that is likely to continue for a while. I managed not to spend much time on games this month. However, I did play a complete game of Civ6, but one game seems like enough for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to mainly work on redoing SHD this month. It already feels better and prettier than the old AHB, so I’m definitely feeling positive. Just need to get it back to the old level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work on SHD (and have basic play possible)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create IPO prototype version 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decide which projects to pursue immediately, and which to put on pause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Excuses - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/09/02/Excuses.html/"/>
        <published>2021-09-02T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/09/02/Excuses.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Time for more excuses! The first half of August went very well. I finished extracting a common code library and restarted AHB, but this time it is called SpaceHex Duel (SHD). Yes, thankyou, I do know I have a special way with naming. At the moment the board is set up and I have started work on the pieces. And then things have paused. I had my first Pfizer vaccine does and a bad reaction.  Over a week was mostly a write-off. I played the Battletech computer game instead of working (it was on sale at Humble Bundle). I have the next dose soon and fingers crossed that goes better!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also ran 2 IPO playtests. The simplifications had mixed results. Continuous growth and card choice worked well. Removing auctions and money generation changes did not work so well. Time for version 4!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work on SHD (and have basic play possible)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create IPO prototype version 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decide which projects to pursue immediately, and which to put on pause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Flat - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/08/02/Flat.html/"/>
        <published>2021-08-02T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2021-08-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/08/02/Flat.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The last month has been a been a total loss as far as gamedev is concerned. There has been barely 2 equivalent days of progress. I’m feeling a little stressed over some housing issues (that should be resolved this week) and this has affected my ability to get things done. I have played quite a few games though - does that count as market research?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasks this month are the same as last month, with the slight change that I have prepped a third version of IPO. I just need to answer certain questions about the game, so the playtest will be more focussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extract and improve common code &amp;amp; prefabs from AHB, mainly the card libraries. Then work on examples in the form of simple games (like AHB v2).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try the third IPO prototype and answer the four gameplay questions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decide which projects to pursue immediately, and which to put on pause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Fast Start, Slow End - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/07/01/Fast-Start-Slow-End.html/"/>
        <published>2021-07-01T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2021-07-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/07/01/Fast-Start-Slow-End.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The start of this month was a rush. I left myself a long TODO list at the end of &lt;a href=&quot;/2021/06/01/Constant-Change.html&quot;&gt;last month&lt;/a&gt;, and I was enthused to get started. First was the hex libraries: done and looking good, ready for an example project. Next was a second IPO prototype: that went well and showed promise, although there are still serious gameplay problems. Then I started working on improving the screen sizing libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is where everything ground to a halt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not because I got stuck. I got demotivated. The sizing work is boring and just needs to be ground through. But it was hard going. Then I got sick (not Covid), and now there is a lockdown (Covid) here again. I’m not feeling much va-va-voom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also still thinking about what to do. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_as_a_service&quot;&gt;SAAS&lt;/a&gt; seems like a nice idea and something technically well within my abilities, but now I’m concerned by maintenance/support issues if I’m not around. Similarly, I’m having second thoughts about Unity3D. Working on the sizing stuff reminds me of various issues I have with it and how I am using an old version. I will probably just keep with it as I can’t think of anything better which doesn’t invole a lot of learning/rewriting (other engines like Unreal) or the same issues as SAAS (HTML5). Hmmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extract and improve common code &amp;amp; prefabs from AHB, mainly the card libraries. Then work on examples in the form of simple games (like AHB v2).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try a third IPO prototype.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decide which projects to pursue immediately, and which to put on pause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>The Only Constant Is Change - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/06/01/Constant-Change.html/"/>
        <published>2021-06-01T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2021-06-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/06/01/Constant-Change.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/05/04/Abandon-Restart.html&quot;&gt;Last month&lt;/a&gt; I announced the cancellation (postponement?) of Abstract Hex Battle. Now I am full of new ideas. Anyway, this month I extracted and improved possibly common code from AHB. There is still some work for the hex library, but that can be done in combination with starting another project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also prototyped IPO and then played it. It has some problems (unsurprsingly). The game is too fast at the start and too fiddly at the end. I still think it has promise, so a second prototype is in the plan for this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might be taking on too much between: the common library; Concealed Intent 2; AHB v2; and IPO. Actually it is worse than that, because I have had another couple of ideas. They are: another card game I’d like prototype if there is time; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_as_a_service&quot;&gt;SAAS&lt;/a&gt; procgen system. I really like the procgen idea, it fits my strengths and avoids weaknesses very well (except for trying to sell the product itself). I really need to decide upon a focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also decided to start month-to-month plans, the adjustable time plans are just  unnecessarily unwieldly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extract and improve common code &amp;amp; prefabs from AHB, mainly the hex and card libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try a second IPO prototype.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decide which projects to pursue immediately, and which to put on pause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Abandon and Restart - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/05/04/Abandon-Restart.html/"/>
        <published>2021-05-04T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2021-05-04T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/05/04/Abandon-Restart.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have abandoned the Abstract Hex Battle project, for now. I started working on the AI and I just couldn’t get it to work properly. The problem was caused by some unfortunate design decisions made early in the project in order to get it up and running quickly. Now those were blocking forward movement. I started reworking the internals for a day, but then stopped. I was not sufficiently excited by the project to put in the effort required to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last fortnight I have been extracting the useful common code and prefabs from Abstract Hex Battle to use as a base for future games. That has gone quite well. Good enough that I extended the work to build in localisation and other extras. There is a little more to do on this task. After that I plan to start a couple of games (maybe a quick rewrite of AHB and/or CI2D) to prove the common code works before starting the next proper project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also started prototyping a card game, IPO. I had the original idea for this game several years ago (&lt;a href=&quot;/2016/08/30/Prototyping.html&quot;&gt;see here&lt;/a&gt;), but couldn’t get it to work in playtests. A couple of weeks ago I had an idea which may fix the initial problems. Now it is time to see if the game can be saved. I hope so, because it is a cool idea combined with an interesting mechanic. Plus, it can be paper prototyped so iterative improvements will be fast and easy to test (much better than a PC game!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next 5 weeks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extract and Improve common code &amp;amp; prefabs from AHB, including simulation engine and card libraries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prototype IPO&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restart AHB as proof-of-concept for the common libraries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;??? (profit!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Getting There - Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/03/15/Getting-There-Progress.html/"/>
        <published>2021-03-15T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2021-03-15T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/03/15/Getting-There-Progress.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It has now been just under 11 months since I started work on this “little” 3-5 month game. It doesn’t even have a proper name yet! However, over the last 6 weeks quite a bit of progress has been made. I spent 5 weeks: completing all the remaining planned animations; fixing all known bugs; adding music/sfx; handling screen sizes up to 1080p (my screen size); and improving the game progression model. The missing week was spent on writing a simple logic library for scripting and organising an almighty mess of downloaded assets into something reasonable so I could find the sounds needed. Of course now there are 2 new bugs and 2 new animations on the todo list, but despite that it feels like the game is moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m about to lose a week to Easter holidays, so I’ll add a week to make a 6 week block next. That will be a year from the start. Fingers crossed, most of the work will be done by then. Looking at the todo list, this is possible. The last big item is fixing the AI. Then error handling, cleaning up the menu and making it prettier wherever possible. And a proper a name of course!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next 6 weeks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Error handling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make the game prettier (especially the menus) and come up with a name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build system&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepare marketing materials &amp;amp; limited buildup with a plan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Release to testers. Setup on &lt;a href=&quot;https://itch.io/&quot;&gt;Itch.io&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; create a build system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>New Year, New Progress Report</title>
        <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/02/05/New-Year-New-Progress.html/"/>
        <published>2021-02-05T00:00:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2021-02-05T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/02/05/New-Year-New-Progress.html/</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As expected &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/12/14/Progress_Report.html&quot;&gt;December was a bad month for progress&lt;/a&gt; on my new game. However,
January went much better. All the animations I wanted to add plus some extras have been completed. Of course along the way I thought of some more, but they will be for later. The gameplay UI has been cleaned up and looks reasonable now (for a programmer anyway). As a result the game is now 2-player only (originally it allowed upto 4 players) as I couldn’t work out how to do a nice UI for more players. Also, I fixed some annoying bugs. There are still a couple of bugs outstanding, but nothing that should crash the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;centre&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/posts/ahb/ahb_20210204.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/ahb/ahb_20210204.png&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; alt=&quot;Abstract Hex Battle WIP&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/centre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are back in lockdown here in Perth. Based on previous experience this gives me more time, but less productivity. So now is the occasion to start the slow work of cleaning up the menus, screen sizing, tooltips and audio - not hard, just time consuming. Then think about balance and feel, since moving to 2-player has made the gameplay feel flat in places. It needs to be amped  up with various modifiers. I have some ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the game still needs a name!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next 4 weeks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve balance and feel of the game&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make the game much prettier and come up with a name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AI, build system &amp;amp; error handling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And after that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepare marketing materials &amp;amp; limited buildup with a plan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Release to testers. Setup on &lt;a href=&quot;https://itch.io/&quot;&gt;Itch.io&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; create a build system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    

</feed>