<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-20T14:28:28+08:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Restart?</title><link href="/2024/11/11/Restart.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Restart?" /><published>2024-11-11T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-11-11T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/2024/11/11/Restart</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/11/11/Restart.html"><![CDATA[<p>Its been a while. So what has been happening? Not much. In the last week I’ve started coding again, but nothing directly gamedev related, although not completely unrelated. I updated my old Scala libraries to the most recent versions of the system and them improved some planet generation code I wrote years ago. Fun, but probably not going anywhere. I also installed Linux Mint on my old 2012 Macbook Pro (as the old OS was creaking and wouldn’t update). It actually works better now - the trackpad used to work intermittently, now it is fine! I wrote and posted this from the laptop.</p>

<p>Really need to get back to doing some work, starting with the much delayed Godot prototype test.</p>

<p>Sometime soon:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Godot prototype</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Posts" /><category term="ProgressReport" /><category term="DevDiary" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Its been a while. So what has been happening? Not much. In the last week I’ve started coding again, but nothing directly gamedev related, although not completely unrelated. I updated my old Scala libraries to the most recent versions of the system and them improved some planet generation code I wrote years ago. Fun, but probably not going anywhere. I also installed Linux Mint on my old 2012 Macbook Pro (as the old OS was creaking and wouldn’t update). It actually works better now - the trackpad used to work intermittently, now it is fine! I wrote and posted this from the laptop. Really need to get back to doing some work, starting with the much delayed Godot prototype test. Sometime soon: Godot prototype]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Linux</title><link href="/2024/06/21/Linux.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linux" /><published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/2024/06/21/Linux</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/06/21/Linux.html"><![CDATA[<p>This update is for June, July &amp; August. I’ve done no significant gamedev work in the last month and some other tasks have come up that mean nothing is likely to be done until mid-August (at the earliest). So no change.</p>

<p>Ok, a little change. My desktop is now Linux, to be exact Ubuntu 24.04 (it has a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Numbat">numbat</a> for a mascot!). I’ve used Windows for over 25 years now, but before  that my home computer was Linux going back to university. Linux still has some annoyances (I guess all OSes do), but it has moved on a long way, and a lot is better than I remember, especially in the ecosystem of programs available. You can even play decent comercial games on it now - what a world we live in.</p>

<p>Sometime:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Godot prototype</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Posts" /><category term="ProgressReport" /><category term="DevDiary" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This update is for June, July &amp; August. I’ve done no significant gamedev work in the last month and some other tasks have come up that mean nothing is likely to be done until mid-August (at the earliest). So no change. Ok, a little change. My desktop is now Linux, to be exact Ubuntu 24.04 (it has a numbat for a mascot!). I’ve used Windows for over 25 years now, but before that my home computer was Linux going back to university. Linux still has some annoyances (I guess all OSes do), but it has moved on a long way, and a lot is better than I remember, especially in the ecosystem of programs available. You can even play decent comercial games on it now - what a world we live in. Sometime: Godot prototype]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nada</title><link href="/2024/05/01/Nada.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nada" /><published>2024-05-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-05-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/2024/05/01/Nada</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/05/01/Nada.html"><![CDATA[<p>How many synonyms are there for nothing? I suspect if my current rate of doing nothing (on gamedev) contines I may find out! No progress in March or April.</p>

<p>Sometime:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Godot prototype</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Posts" /><category term="ProgressReport" /><category term="DevDiary" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How many synonyms are there for nothing? I suspect if my current rate of doing nothing (on gamedev) contines I may find out! No progress in March or April. Sometime: Godot prototype]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">No Marketing?</title><link href="/2024/03/01/Marketing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No Marketing?" /><published>2024-03-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-03-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/2024/03/01/Marketing</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/03/01/Marketing.html"><![CDATA[<p>Last month I finished the little webtool idea - at least enough that it worked. Of course doing a very barebones MVP generated an extremely long list of possible improvements. Not going to post the details, as I am not certain I’ll do anymore work on it. The result is out of my usual area so I’m not sure if its worth making it user-friendly and then marketing it. I doubt my ability to sell it and even if I did a good job, I have little confidence it would generate much income. So I’ll keep it on the back burner, and get to trying to create Godot prototype for now. Didn’t manage to properly start that task last month, just reading and prep, so time to get coding.</p>

<p>This month:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Godot prototype</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Posts" /><category term="ProgressReport" /><category term="DevDiary" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month I finished the little webtool idea - at least enough that it worked. Of course doing a very barebones MVP generated an extremely long list of possible improvements. Not going to post the details, as I am not certain I’ll do anymore work on it. The result is out of my usual area so I’m not sure if its worth making it user-friendly and then marketing it. I doubt my ability to sell it and even if I did a good job, I have little confidence it would generate much income. So I’ll keep it on the back burner, and get to trying to create Godot prototype for now. Didn’t manage to properly start that task last month, just reading and prep, so time to get coding. This month: Godot prototype]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alternatives</title><link href="/2024/02/02/Alternatives.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alternatives" /><published>2024-02-02T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-02-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/2024/02/02/Alternatives</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/02/02/Alternatives.html"><![CDATA[<p>I am becoming increasingly unimpressed with Javascript based gamedev. Perhaps it is time for trying another engine. In the meantime, I have been trying out Javascript for something it is very good at - websites. I reimplemented the SHD online feedback/stats engine using it in under a week. The tooling around JS is much better than I’m accustomed. Such a smooth process and it puts doing anything in Scala to shame. Now I am trying to create a tiny MVP web tool, it shouldn’t take too long. After that I’m going to try the <a href="https://godotengine.org/">Godot game engine</a>. The buzz is that it has improved greatly over the last 6 months and my initial dismissal may no longer be valid. After that I just need to choose an engine and stick with it.</p>

<p>This month:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Other non-game-prototype</li>
  <li>Godot prototype</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Posts" /><category term="ProgressReport" /><category term="DevDiary" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am becoming increasingly unimpressed with Javascript based gamedev. Perhaps it is time for trying another engine. In the meantime, I have been trying out Javascript for something it is very good at - websites. I reimplemented the SHD online feedback/stats engine using it in under a week. The tooling around JS is much better than I’m accustomed. Such a smooth process and it puts doing anything in Scala to shame. Now I am trying to create a tiny MVP web tool, it shouldn’t take too long. After that I’m going to try the Godot game engine. The buzz is that it has improved greatly over the last 6 months and my initial dismissal may no longer be valid. After that I just need to choose an engine and stick with it. This month: Other non-game-prototype Godot prototype]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nothing</title><link href="/2024/01/02/Coop.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nothing" /><published>2024-01-02T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-01-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/2024/01/02/Coop</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/01/02/Coop.html"><![CDATA[<p>So there was some progress, just nothing with gamedev. I worked on various admin and household tasks. For instance, I designed and built the chicken coop below.</p>

<center><img src="/assets/posts/general/chicken_coop.png" alt="Chicken coop" /></center>

<p>Last month, next month and the month after:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Typescript/Babylon.js tests and prototype</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Posts" /><category term="ProgressReport" /><category term="DevDiary" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So there was some progress, just nothing with gamedev. I worked on various admin and household tasks. For instance, I designed and built the chicken coop below. Last month, next month and the month after: Typescript/Babylon.js tests and prototype]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nothing</title><link href="/2023/12/01/Nothing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nothing" /><published>2023-12-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-12-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/2023/12/01/Nothing</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/12/01/Nothing.html"><![CDATA[<p>Is it a progress report when there is no progress?</p>

<p>Last month, next month and the month after:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Typescript/Babylon.js tests and prototype</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Posts" /><category term="ProgressReport" /><category term="DevDiary" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is it a progress report when there is no progress? Last month, next month and the month after: Typescript/Babylon.js tests and prototype]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rewrite</title><link href="/2023/11/02/Rewrite.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rewrite" /><published>2023-11-02T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-11-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/2023/11/02/Rewrite</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/11/02/Rewrite.html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the last month I have continued rewriting my libraries for the third time, currently into Typescript, having given up on Scala. I still like Scala. It would be my favorite language to code in, if I never wanted to actually deliver anything. Unfortunately its tooling is atrocious. It is a common (and usually hyperbolic) trope to claim that a language is dying. While I’m not going to say that, mainly due to experience, the Scala community does not feel thriving. Typescript was the obvious choice since I was transpiling Scala into Javascript anyway to use the Babylon.js library. The process has been very smooth (especially the IDE tools). Still, I’m not sure its the right decision - Rust with various game engines or C# with Godot being the  other contenders.</p>

<p>Work has been slow due to various around-the-house tasks that need to be done before the summer heat arrives. Still In a week or so I should be back where I was before going to China, but in a new language. Then I get back to implementing more prototype/test code towards the next game.</p>

<p>Last month, next month and the month after:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Typescript/Babylon.js tests and prototype</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Posts" /><category term="ProgressReport" /><category term="DevDiary" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last month I have continued rewriting my libraries for the third time, currently into Typescript, having given up on Scala. I still like Scala. It would be my favorite language to code in, if I never wanted to actually deliver anything. Unfortunately its tooling is atrocious. It is a common (and usually hyperbolic) trope to claim that a language is dying. While I’m not going to say that, mainly due to experience, the Scala community does not feel thriving. Typescript was the obvious choice since I was transpiling Scala into Javascript anyway to use the Babylon.js library. The process has been very smooth (especially the IDE tools). Still, I’m not sure its the right decision - Rust with various game engines or C# with Godot being the other contenders. Work has been slow due to various around-the-house tasks that need to be done before the summer heat arrives. Still In a week or so I should be back where I was before going to China, but in a new language. Then I get back to implementing more prototype/test code towards the next game. Last month, next month and the month after: Typescript/Babylon.js tests and prototype]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Smug Mode</title><link href="/2023/10/01/Smug-Mode.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Smug Mode" /><published>2023-10-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-10-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/2023/10/01/Smug-Mode</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/10/01/Smug-Mode.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m just back from a month-long overseas holiday. So no signiticant work has been done since the last report, and the coming month will be
spent getting back up to speed. That is the progress report, but …</p>

<p>While I was away Unity announced a new pricing policy, suffered a huge developer backlash, and then <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/unity-software-rolls-back-parts-new-pricing-policy-after-backlash-2023-09-22/">rolled most of it back</a>. The important change was the addition a of a per-install fee on all Unity games, even those that were made under a previous versions of Unity (which supposedly have unchangeable terms &amp; conditions). There were also concerns around what counted as an install and how it would be measured. The rollback has kept the per-install fee, but removed the retroactivity and added a high install hurdle before fees accrue. The impression is that many developers feel this is good enough. I don’t.</p>

<p>I have two Unity games available. Both Concealed Intent and SpaceHexDuel are written using Unity v5, first released in 2015 and last updated in 2019. Both were released long before these new fees were announced and both are far from clearing the install hurdle. So they should be safe from Unity’s capriciousness. However, the idea that Unity could change the terms of the agreement I had with them from nearly 10 years ago (when I purchased the engine, there has been no money or purchases since) just removes any trust I have in them. Honestly, fuck Unity!</p>

<p>Luckily, I have a small headstart on abandoning Unity - thus the smugness. Back in April <a href="https://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2023/04/03/Annoyance.html">I wrote how I was too annoyed by Unity to keep using it</a>. After a brief dalliance with Three.js I decided to use Babylon.js as my new engine. Since then I haven’t gotten far due to various distractions (like being out of the country for a month). Now there is a flood of devs away from Unity and most seem to be going to Godot. Did I make the right choice? I don’t know. Time to create some prototypes to find out!</p>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Posts" /><category term="ProgressReport" /><category term="DevDiary" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m just back from a month-long overseas holiday. So no signiticant work has been done since the last report, and the coming month will be spent getting back up to speed. That is the progress report, but … While I was away Unity announced a new pricing policy, suffered a huge developer backlash, and then rolled most of it back. The important change was the addition a of a per-install fee on all Unity games, even those that were made under a previous versions of Unity (which supposedly have unchangeable terms &amp; conditions). There were also concerns around what counted as an install and how it would be measured. The rollback has kept the per-install fee, but removed the retroactivity and added a high install hurdle before fees accrue. The impression is that many developers feel this is good enough. I don’t. I have two Unity games available. Both Concealed Intent and SpaceHexDuel are written using Unity v5, first released in 2015 and last updated in 2019. Both were released long before these new fees were announced and both are far from clearing the install hurdle. So they should be safe from Unity’s capriciousness. However, the idea that Unity could change the terms of the agreement I had with them from nearly 10 years ago (when I purchased the engine, there has been no money or purchases since) just removes any trust I have in them. Honestly, fuck Unity! Luckily, I have a small headstart on abandoning Unity - thus the smugness. Back in April I wrote how I was too annoyed by Unity to keep using it. After a brief dalliance with Three.js I decided to use Babylon.js as my new engine. Since then I haven’t gotten far due to various distractions (like being out of the country for a month). Now there is a flood of devs away from Unity and most seem to be going to Godot. Did I make the right choice? I don’t know. Time to create some prototypes to find out!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning</title><link href="/2023/08/01/Learning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning" /><published>2023-08-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-08-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/2023/08/01/Learning</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/08/01/Learning.html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the last month I have continued learning the Scala.js/Babylon.js environment by creating a prototype for my next game. Progress is slow but steady, and no blockers have been hit so far. I consider that a success. Progress will continue being slow for the next 2 months at least. Partially because it is new, and many of the familiar tools are missing, but also because there will be some large disruptions in my non-work life over the next couple of months. For that reason, do not expect a progress report next month. Although no loss, as it would just be more of the same.</p>

<p>Last month, next month and the month after:</p>

<ul>
  <li>More Scala.js/Babylon.js tests</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Charles</name></author><category term="Posts" /><category term="ProgressReport" /><category term="DevDiary" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last month I have continued learning the Scala.js/Babylon.js environment by creating a prototype for my next game. Progress is slow but steady, and no blockers have been hit so far. I consider that a success. Progress will continue being slow for the next 2 months at least. Partially because it is new, and many of the familiar tools are missing, but also because there will be some large disruptions in my non-work life over the next couple of months. For that reason, do not expect a progress report next month. Although no loss, as it would just be more of the same. Last month, next month and the month after: More Scala.js/Babylon.js tests]]></summary></entry></feed>