<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jarrah Technology</title>
    <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Jarrah Technology</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 11:03:34 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 11:03:34 +0800</lastBuildDate>

    
    <item>
      <title>Annoyance</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2023/04/03/Annoyance.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2023/04/03/Annoyance</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month split into 4 parts. First the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2023/03/12/Space-Hex-Duel-1.1.html&quot;&gt;1.1 version of Space Hex Duel was completed and released&lt;/a&gt;. Next I worked on testing out new tools and setting up the Ci2D dev environment. Then I gave up on that in annoyance and just did some fun coding before finishing with a holiday to Adelaide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What annoyed me? Unity. In particular Unity 5.6, and the lack of support in modern libraries and technologies. Admittedly that version is about 6 years old, but it is the version I own (forever) and the prices have risen significantly for the current version. Do I really want to spend the money for an update? I don’t need any of the big new features, but there will come a time that I just won’t be able to build and run with the old version anymore. Already VS Code (my IDE) no longer supports the version of .Net required by 5.6 (I had to trick it to work productively). I don’t want to end up trapped. So it is time to investigate my options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stay on Unity 5.6 and suck it up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move to the current free version of Unity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move to the current paid version of Unity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move to a similar open source engine like Godot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move to another big (but quite different) engine like Unreal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move to a Javascript engine (like Tyrian or Babylon) and release to the web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They all have their pros &amp;amp; cons (maybe I’ll write a post about them). For now I am going to check out some Javascript options, largely because those are the ones I know least about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also I learnt that I should restrict the ordering of actions in turn-based games to reduce the space of possible actions. This will make the search space for AI much smaller. For example, in SHD it is possible to shoot or place your piece in any order. Just changing this (eg forcing the player to place before shooting) would reduce the possible moves in a turn by orders of magnitude in the worst case (when there are lots of bases). I must remember this in future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Done last month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finished and released SHD 1.1 (and did a little marketing)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setup Ci2D in Unity 5.6&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Investigated AI, Rewired, and updated libraries - none would work for SHD&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added steam manager to common Unity utilities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hex library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tasks for this month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish the hex library&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Investigate other game engines (starting with Javascript ones)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space Hex Duel 1.1 Released!</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2023/03/12/Space-Hex-Duel-1.1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2023/03/12/Space-Hex-Duel-1.1</guid>
      <description>&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jarrahtech.itch.io/spacehexduel&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/ahb/capsule_lg.png&quot; alt=&quot;Space Hex Duel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 1.1 patch of Space Hex Duel is now released and out on &lt;a href=&quot;https://jarrahtech.itch.io/spacehexduel&quot;&gt;Itch.io&lt;/a&gt; (and still PWYW - effectively free!). It is actually quite small release, there were no game breaking bugs, so this is mainly “quality of life” improvements. Normally this would be version 1.0.1, but there are a couple of extra screens to support an online connection (feedback page, news display on the main page), so I bumped it to 1.1. Other notable changes include: a timeout on the good AI so It doesn’t sit for minutes in hard situations looking for the best possible move; and a reworded tutorial with a YouTube video (embedded at the bottom of this post) for those who just want to jump straight in. The full changelist is below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up I should start some prototyping work for my next game. Although I’m considering releasing Space Hex Duel to Steam at some point, which will require a few extra tasks. So maybe a 1.2 release in a few months to add those?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Space Hex Duel 1.1.0 (13th March 2023)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add Online support (if no connection do nothing and continue)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add feedback page&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add JarrahTech news box&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Collect anonymous stats on player progress and locale&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AI
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;if shooting does not destroy anything, then try the next base’s shooting rather than check if a drop is possible (as no new spaces will have appeared)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;time limit stored in config file (timeout_seconds), defaults to 15 seconds - use  the best plan found so far if time expires&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;try (a little) not to put bases that will be immediately destroyed right next to the players home&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change Tutorial text and ensure colours and controls referred to are correct when displayed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Code signed the executable (with a self-created certificate)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make tutorial skippable and add a link to a YouTube video of the tutorial&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dropped bombs make a small explosion even if they don’t destroy what they are on&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set explosions to be at the top of the render queue so they are not hidden by planets/bases&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fix tooltip for unclaimed powerup hexes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stop unlocks running over menu if there are lots of them on game over screen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Give different enemy types different names&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jarrahtechnology.com/games/spacehexduel&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jarrahtechnology.com/press/spacehexduel.html&quot;&gt;Presskit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jarrahtech.itch.io/spacehexduel&quot;&gt;Storefront&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://itch.io/embed/1823532?linkback=true&quot; width=&quot;552&quot; height=&quot;167&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jarrahtech.itch.io/spacehexduel&quot;&gt;Space Hex Duel by JarrahTech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;iframe height=&quot;167&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/dvyQinkVeHk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solid Month - Progress Report</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2023/03/01/Solid.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2023/03/01/Solid</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;February was a solid month. Nothing flashy or fancy, but just clearing the task list. Not bad considering I lost probably 4-5 complete days to tasks around the house. A couple of interesting issues arose. It turns out that the version of .Net Unity 5.6 uses does not support TLS1.2+ so doesn’t work on recent web services - like the host I deployed the generic server. That took a little fiddling to get working. Before working out a solution, for a couple of days, I thought the whole thing would need to be scrapped - I was not a happy boy! Also realised I needed to change the server to build-in internationalisation of strings - that was was fiddly, but not hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SHD patch release is not done, but very close. Now I just need to: finish up the tutorial changes; record a video of me doing the tutorial; and then final testing. There is a good chance this will be complete in early March. Then hopefully my Internet will hold up long enough to do a little marketing. I’ll be losing a week due to holidays, so just those few tasks are the goals for the month. If there is time after that there always things to do: start Ci2d; improve the generic server; write libraries. I’ll work it out when the time comes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Done last month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generic game server deployed and integrated with SHD using a replicated DB&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reorganised SHD code to split out a Common Unity Toolkit as a submodule&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AI Timeout &amp;amp; other improvements in SHD&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Started on SHD tutorial rework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tasks for this month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Release SHD 1.1 and market it a little&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Coding - Progress Report</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2023/02/02/Happy-Coding.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2023/02/02/Happy-Coding</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was a surprise with the JarrahTech end of month summary. I was expecting to require a whole load of excuses why I did so few hours of work. I still have those excuses (I have been spending many hours doing maintenance on the house), but it turns out they are not needed. Without realising it, I have spend a respectable amount of time completing a basic generic game server. It was a mostly enjoyable process where I tried out a load of new libraries and technologies, so maybe that is why the time just disappeared?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the generic server is largely done. The functionality needed at this stage is all there, but a couple of unexpected &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; related issues came up in a test deploy (database replication and external logging). When they are done I’ll write the integration into SHD and then the patch release. Still looking good for this month. I’m not sure I chose the best technology for the server, but I’m not redoing it now - maybe later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had a chat with people about what game I should develop next. In a complete non-surprise it will be Concealed Intent 2D (a working title, not the final name). It will combine the stealth focused synchronous turn-based spaceship combat of Concealed Intent with a procgen rogue-like and on a flat 2D map (rather than full 3D). Two other ideas also caught people’s attention. As a result there may be some background work on the IPO card game, and maybe a little experimentation towards something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Done last month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finished generic game server (stats, feedback, news, etc …)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chose Concealed Intent 2D (ci2d) as my next project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tasks for this month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deploy generic game server&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work on (and hopefully complete) a 1.1 patch release for SHD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inevitable - Progress Report</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2023/01/04/Inevitable.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2023/01/04/Inevitable</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The big news from last month is &lt;a href=&quot;https://jarrahtech.itch.io/spacehexduel&quot;&gt;Space Hex Duel is released&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan was to take the rest of December dealing with a little marketing, the holidays and do some coding for fun before choosing the next project. Well I managed two of those. My internet connection died the day after release and only got repaired nearly a fortnight later, so not much marketing. There have been seven downloads of the game and two people got back to me - one liked it (and paid for it despite being PWYW - thanks!), the other had difficulty with the tutorial. Thanks to the feedback and some of my own thoughts, I now have a couple of things to change. Time for a patch release. It probably won’t be for this month, but hopefully early Feb it will be done. Then I’ll do some more marketing and revisit a possible Steam release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also back working on a generic online game server. Not for playing SHD online, but to handle all the other stuff like feedback, game stats, etc. As part of the patch release I will build this into SHD. It will be in keeping with the original idea of SHD as a testbed for new libraries. As for the next project, last month I had 5 ideas worth pursuing, which I have now whittled down to 6 (I had a good idea for a simple card-battler). Hmmmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Done last month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little fixes in SHD&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Released SHD to Itch with a little marketing and support&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rework internal Scala libraries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Worked on generic game server (stats, feedback, news, etc …)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tasks for this month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish generic game server&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work on patch release for SHD&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Think about next project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space Hex Duel Released!</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/12/09/Space-Hex-Duel-Released.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/12/09/Space-Hex-Duel-Released</guid>
      <description>&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jarrahtech.itch.io/spacehexduel&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/ahb/capsule_lg.png&quot; alt=&quot;Space Hex Duel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is done! Space Hex Duel is now available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://jarrahtech.itch.io/spacehexduel&quot;&gt;Itch.io&lt;/a&gt; as a Pay-What-You-Want (PWYW) download (suggested donation: US$2).
I recommend interested people download it for free, and if they enjoy it and would like to say thankyou, then go back and donate. I chose PWYW as a test - to get as
many people as possible playing and see if it has any potential. Also, because it has not been playtested by anyone other than myself - hopefully there will
not be many issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;iframe height=&quot;167&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/62viGwySbjk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

    &lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://itch.io/embed/1823532?linkback=true&quot; width=&quot;552&quot; height=&quot;167&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jarrahtech.itch.io/spacehexduel&quot;&gt;Space Hex Duel by JarrahTech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the basic marketing material see above and:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jarrahtechnology.com/games/spacehexduel&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jarrahtechnology.com/press/spacehexduel.html&quot;&gt;Presskit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jarrahtech.itch.io/spacehexduel&quot;&gt;Storefront&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what next?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first task will be to let people know the game is released. Time to dust off my mailing list and Twitter/Mastodon accounts. Probably a few other places too. If nothing else it is good practice.
Next, fix any bugs that come up. Since I should have tons of time apart from bugfixing (&lt;em&gt;fingers crossed&lt;/em&gt;), I need to decide what to do next. I have 5 possibilities, from the obvious (Concealed Intent 2D) to the unusual (not telling yet!). I also need to decide if I should release this game to Steam. I’m tempted, just because Steam is so big compared to everyone else in PC games that if it is not there then the game will be obscure. However, releasing to Steam will require some extra work, and I don’t want to start that yet. Instead I will mostly spend the few weeks mostly on just-for-fun programming and household tasks. The plan being to start the new year on the next game (and if decide to do it, Steam).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Holidays.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So Close - Progress Report</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/12/04/So-Close.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/12/04/So-Close</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ahhh, I am agonisingly close to release! This progress report is delayed a few days because I thought I could get it out yesterday. The game is complete (enough :). However, I forgot how long it takes to make a trailer video and other marketing materials. Now the plan is to release by Friday (9th). The trailer should be done on Monday, but then there is copy/images for various forums (Itch, website, IndieDB, mailing list, …) and I have decided to have another go at improving the AI time estimation function (presently it can be badly wrong).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My TODO list for the month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Release!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;???&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Profit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasks completed last month were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finished Tutorial&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved UI and text&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lots of QA/bugfixing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Started creating marketing materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Or Never - Progress Report</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/11/01/Now-Or-Never.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/11/01/Now-Or-Never</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A little change to format in this progress report. Rather than say what I hope to achieve, instead the below list is SHD’s remaining tasks (in order). It is also my current plan. The goal is the release of SHD to Itch.io by the end of the month. That is it. This section comes first, because I’m focussed on the finish. Tasks 1 &amp;amp; 4 may take some time; the rest should be fairly straightforward (fingers crossed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tutorial&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Translations: remove non-english and check text&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Possible small changes: should blast self-destruct? how many levels use dumb AI?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clean/test/build&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Itch.io: build, screenshots, cover image &amp;amp; release&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month I ruthlessly culled the list of remaining tasks. This game need to be finished ASAP. The AI component is good enough. I could work on it for many months if I wanted, but won’t. The online component is dropped, the feedback screen is gone. The project’s README file now has over a dozen other possible small improvements, plus a few of bigger ones (but was online play ever a real possibility?). I don’t expect to revisit them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasks completed last month were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finished AI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Completed UI sizing for different screen sizes (this took most of the time, especially tracking down a DPI scaling bug)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updated splash screen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bugfixes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Started on tutorial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, time to get back to it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need For Speed - Progress Report</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/10/03/Need-For-Speed.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/10/03/Need-For-Speed</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you looked at SHD a month ago and again today, you would probably notice no difference at all. However, behind the scenes a great deal has changed. Over the last month my main task has been improving the AI. It soon became clear a major issue was speed. Examining a set of moves took several milliseconds (ms), and there were often thousands of possible moves, sometimes tens of thousands - it was taking too long. In speeding up the analysis, errors began creeping into the system caused by timing and threading issues. Hmmm. I decided to change the way the engine worked so that these errors could not occur and managed to get this largely complete in a week. The result was that average analysis time for a single set of moves went from 5ms to 0.19ms, error free. Proud of that work. It  should be fast enough to let the AI to look more than one move ahead - which is the next task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got a little distracted by possible future projects. Now have another good idea for the next project. Hard decisions will need to be made soon around what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SHD tasks for November are the same as before, just the AI is now very close to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month’s completed tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moved SHD engine from a Plan/Action pattern to a Command/Effect pattern&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AI working well, just speeding up code so that can process more scenarios in reasonable time (5ms to 0.19ms so far)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Played with setups &amp;amp; org for next project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bugfixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full AI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little improvements &amp;amp; bugfixes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next version of prototypes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Online component&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try not to get distracted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light At The End Of The Tunnel - Progress Report</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/09/01/Light-Tunnel.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/09/01/Light-Tunnel</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The point has been reached where the end is so near, I find my attention waning and drifting to other projects. This month I spent nearly a record low number of hours on SHD, and yet my todo list is still quite short. Today I went through the list of ideas/issues/features remaining. Most are not worth doing, or are code improvements for the next game (they will make no significant difference to this one). The ones left I grouped by theme and numbered by importance - the last is #5. The first is the long-planned full AI; second is the online componenent. The others are not worth mentioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what did I do this past month? The first couple of weeks was spent finishing off the r/roguelikedev tutorial event &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/08/17/Roguelike.html&quot;&gt;(see this post for more info)&lt;/a&gt;. Then I spent some (too much!) time moving all my websites from &lt;a href=&quot;www.linode.com&quot;&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;www.github.com&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. Not because I’m unhappy with Linode (they have been great), but to same time by not managing my own virtual servers for a couple of simple static websites. Then I did a little daydreaming of ideas. Lastly a few hours fixing up bugs, tooltips and unlocks before starting work on the AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SHD tasks for the coming month are to just finish the damn thing (maybe not this month, but hopefully next).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month’s completed tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little improvements &amp;amp; bugfixes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move websites/repos to free hosts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;r/roguelikedev tutorial event complete &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/08/17/Roguelike.html&quot;&gt;(see this post to play)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multi-frame AI framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full AI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little improvements &amp;amp; bugfixes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next version of prototypes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Online component&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try not to get distracted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roguelike Tutorial 2022</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/08/17/Roguelike.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/08/17/Roguelike</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a distraction from other things I should have been doing over the last 6 weeks, I completed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/roguelikedev/comments/vhfsda/roguelikedev_does_the_complete_roguelike_tutorial/&quot;&gt;/r/roguelikedev Tutorial 2022&lt;/a&gt;. An event to teach people how to write roguelike games like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NetHack&quot;&gt;Nethack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Angband_%28video_game%29&quot;&gt;Angband&lt;/a&gt;, and my old favourite, &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2016/07/omega.html&quot;&gt;Omega&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to learn some &lt;a href=&quot;https://javascript.info/&quot;&gt;Javascript&lt;/a&gt;, and this seemed a good way to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is done now. There is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jarrahtech.github.io/RoguelikeTutorial2022/&quot;&gt;playable version here&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jarrahtech/RoguelikeTutorial2022&quot;&gt;source code is here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The controls are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;movement/target: arrow keys or wasd (+qezx)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;look: ‘/’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pickup: ‘p’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;message history: ‘v’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;drop/leave: ‘l’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;activate/use/equip: ‘u’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;character screen: ‘c’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/jarrahtech/RoguelikeTutorial2022/blob/main/assets/img/logo.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;/r/roguelikedev Tutorial2022 Logo&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joining The Club - Progress Report</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/08/01/Joining-The-Club.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/08/01/Joining-The-Club</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In July I joined the club - the Covid19 club. Luckily it was a fairly mild case but it still stopped work for nearly a fortnight (2 days in bed, a few days feeling sick and then a week super-tired). As a result I did very few hours on SHD, especially since the few hours I did spend coding were for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://old.reddit.com/r/roguelikedev/comments/vhfsda/roguelikedev_does_the_complete_roguelike_tutorial/&quot;&gt;/r/roguelikedev annual tutorial event&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jarrahtech/RoguelikeTutorial2022&quot;&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://jarrahtech.github.io/RoguelikeTutorial2022/&quot;&gt;playable version&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So achievements are light this months. I have completed weeks 2 through 5 in the /r/roguelikedev challenge, with only 3 more weeks left. It has been worth doing (learning Javascript can only be useful) and without the structure I doubt I would have bothered. Given me a few more ideas to add to the list. As for SHD, I added and hooked up all the remaining planned unlocks/achievements. Plus a few bugfixes, that is it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SHD tasks for the coming month are the same as last month: AI and cleanup. I’ll hopefully also get to move the websites, and of course, the last 3 weeks of the r/roguelikedev event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month’s completed tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wk 2-5 /r/roguelikedev tutorial event&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All unlocks/achievements done&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some bugfixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full AI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little improvements &amp;amp; bugfixes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next version of prototypes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move websites/repos to free hosts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Online component&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;complete r/roguelikedev tutorial event&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holiday - Progress Report</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/07/01/Holiday.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/07/01/Holiday</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As expected June was a truncated month. A weeks holiday interstate and a couple of days dealing with house issues (the joys of living in an old house) put a big hole in my productivity and definitely slowed progress as I lost momentum. Maybe that is what has lead to me deciding to join the &lt;a href=&quot;https://old.reddit.com/r/roguelikedev/comments/vhfsda/roguelikedev_does_the_complete_roguelike_tutorial/&quot;&gt;/r/roguelikedev annual tutorial event&lt;/a&gt;. “Wait,” you say, “don’t you need to finish SHD first before starting another game?” Yes, you are right. This is almost certainly a bad use of my time, especially since I am trying it in a Javascript, a language I haven’t used properly in over 20 years (also, trying to relearn Git &amp;amp; Github at the same time). However, I think it might be useful for future work and I hope to spend no more than one day per week on getting it going (Week 1 took 2 hours, so far so good). If you want to see the WIP, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jarrahtech/RoguelikeTutorial2022&quot;&gt;repo is here&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jarrahtech.github.io/RoguelikeTutorial2022/&quot;&gt;playable version here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SHD is still getting very close to the end now too (about time!). I have added a bunch of new gameplay mechanics: base recharging; base powerups; and bombs. Last time I said the game quickly devolved into a slow defensive slog. Now, not so much. It is not a great game, although definitely a little better than before - and importantly, shorter! There was also some visual improvements and work on achievements. Not the best month in terms of hours worked, but there is clear progress. It was gratifying to see how easily the new mechancis were added due to the earlier framework tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remaining SHD tasks are now AI and cleanup. That is the plan for the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month’s completed tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wk 1 /r/roguelikedev tutorial event&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reorganised achievements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little visual improvements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reworked gameplay to make game faster more interesting - recharge, powerup bases, bomb hex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finalise unlocks/achievements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full AI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little improvements &amp;amp; bugfixes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next version of prototypes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move websites/repos to free hosts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Online component&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;r/roguelikedev tutorial event&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Done? - Progress Report</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/06/01/Done.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/06/01/Done</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;May was a solid month of work. Could have bee a record if not for losing 4 complete days to sickness and probably lower productivity for a few days after. There is a new AI and lots of little improvements. If a player want to keep going forever there is also now an “infinite” mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest task completed was the engine rework - now finished and all (known) resulting bugs cleared. It took 6 weeks total. I thought in the best case it would require nearly 2 weeks, but gave myself 4 weeks due to experience :) So 6 weeks is not great, but not bad. Of course not all the time was taken with refactoring, there was also some prototype and time and a jaunt into the land of node servers and docker (just to learn about them) along the way, but that sort of thing is expected. Still think it was worth it, the final code is much better and more flexible! I’m happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;June will be a short month (I’m away for a week), so of course I have a totally unrealistic list of tasks. The big one is to improve the gameplay. Playing against the new AI quickly results in a defensive slog of a game - not what I had intended. Hopefully I can think of some ways to improve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month’s completed tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rework engine complete&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New AI - but now game bogs down into defensive slogs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Infinite mode&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little visual improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve gameplay?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rearrange unlocks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full AI (current version does not take advantage of all gameplay possibilities)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next version of prototypes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move websites/repos to free hosts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look at online component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactoring - Progress Report</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/05/02/Refactoring.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/05/02/Refactoring</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;April was a month of steady progress. I managed to get 3 games of the IPO prototype played and one of the Ci2d prototype. All went surprisingly well considering expectations. In particular the Ci2d prototype was not completely broken, it played (as intended) like a simplified version of the original - definitely will put some more work into a v2. The mechanics of IPO are fairly steady now. The game drags a little in the mid-game, but that is because I removed some of the more interactive cards (I hope). Now I will try to derive a formula for card strength and add back the interesting cards so combos can be built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rework of SHD’s engine is continuing. It works and is so pretty. Now it just needs to be fully implemented and the old code removed. Hopefully that will complete be before the end of this month. Strangely the new system went through a few design changes to handle cases I didn’t initially consider, and now it looks a lot like the engine in CI (just more abstract). Hmmmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month’s completed tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Played IPO v4 prototype x3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Played Ci2D v1 prototype x1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rework engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish work to improve and componentise/abstract the action system, plus AI (basically build a reusable simulation engine as a backend component)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fix infinite mode, separate  random mode, and rearrange unlocks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better AI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Play new prototypes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sticking Point? - Progress Report</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/04/05/Sticking-Point.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/04/05/Sticking-Point</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have now reached the same point in SHD where I stopped AHB (the “prototype” that went too far). When I decided to stop and restart, I estimated that the work required to fix the problems would take weeks and not be worth the effort. I think the same work will take a week or two with SHD - much better. Also, once done it should be reusable for other turn-based gamedev. Of course I reached that point less half way through the last month, so why isn’t it finished? Well, I haven’t started yet. Instead those distractions (household work and a one week holiday) I mentioned last month took focus. Knowing this was going to happen I worked on tabletop prototypes and little tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month’s completed tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IPO v4 prototype (unplayed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ci2D v1 prototype (unplayed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Level loading system &amp;amp; screen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simple AI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio setup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve and componentise/abstract the action system and AI (basically build a reusable simulation engine as a backend component)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fix infinite mode, separate  random mode, and rearrange unlocks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better AI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Play new prototypes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short Month, Record Hours - Progress Report</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/03/01/Short-Month-Record-Hours.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/03/01/Short-Month-Record-Hours</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite being the shortest month of the year, the February was my best for hours worked. Mainly due to one week being almost full-time on the game - the benefit of it being too hot to be outside (ahh, I love my A/C). I’m not going to publicise the hours I worked - it is still well below my (already low) target. However, in the last report I wrote that I hoped to complete: targetting, shooting, extra actions, handle the end of a game, and unlocks. I did all of that and more: context sensitive tooltips and some framework niceties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this month is not expected to be as productive. There are several house related tasks that got paused waiting for more inclement temperatures - and today the weather turned! Despite this I expect good progress as the biggest task remaining is the AI, and after no further significant functionality is planned (online multiplayer would be such an item, but I’d want to have a version on stores before starting that). Instead, it is all things to make the game prettier and nicer. Thus, I have added a couple of new tasks to the possibles for the month - new prototypes and some library work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work on SHD (play screen, AI, playability improvements)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create IPO prototype version 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decide which projects to pursue immediately, and which to put on pause.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First paper prototypes for the next 1 or 2 games&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common library work (card and backporting SHD stuff)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Again? - Progress Report</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/02/02/Moving-Again.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/02/02/Moving-Again</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before compiling the results for January, I was a little disappointed in myself. I remember it taking a couple of weeks to get moving as other home tasks took precedence. However, after going through my notes, the result looks more like a normal month - a couple of better than average weeks after a couple of worse than average weeks. Consistency is my problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is coming along nicely. The UI is complete and working well (apart from tooltips, to be done later). Forming and moving bases is complete; targeting and firing is in progress. Everything so far works better than before. Perhaps the second time I know better what is required - a point of evidence in favour of prototypes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another two entries have been added onto the game ideas list - time to start culling it. I have also bought some tabletop components as I have plans to create tabletop prototypes of my next games - it is such a great way of iterating through designs quickly. With these new components I will be able to prototype Ci2d, plus a couple of others. I just need a week or so to come up with a set of starting rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work on SHD (targetting, shooting, extra action, end of game &amp;amp; unlocks)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create IPO prototype version 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decide which projects to pursue immediately, and which to put on pause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standstill - Progress Report</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/01/02/Standstill.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2022/01/02/Standstill</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we ring in the new year, it occurred to me that my current game is about at the same playable state as this time last year. Hmmmm.
Of course, I now have a reusable library (hopefully, the test will be in the reuse) and the code is much nicer. However, it seems
as bit poor to make no progress on the ultimate measure of a game - its playability and fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last month the game has become playable again. The turn structure is in and stamps complete. I’ve have also replaced the
health/strength/time displays with shader based radial sprites, rather than the weird looking 3D line drawings in a 2D world. Work has now started on the player UI - my worst gamedev skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been no work on IPO, but I am getting more ideas for various games. I need to get this one finished before my interest wanes, as I feel it doing. I started December with a rush, but that slowed greatly over the fortnight for Christmas and New Years. I need to get back that previous productivity. Time sinks over the next month include a ton of house issues (old houses!), but thanks to the current pandemic lockdown and heatwave, exercise time is minimal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work on SHD (get UI working)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create IPO prototype version 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decide which projects to pursue immediately, and which to put on pause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housework - Progress Report</title>
      <link>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/12/06/Housework.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jarrahtechnology.com/2021/12/06/Housework</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you notice I missed a month? October started well with work on cleaning up the display before adding drag and drop (the main game mechanism).
There was also some work to improve the config options and putting the source repo on a remote server so I can work anywhere with Internet (not just on my home PC).
Then by the end of that month everything stopped, and stayed stopped through November.
There are now three people living in this house and it took some time cleaning up and fixing various things in readiness for their arrival.
Followed by more tasks as they settled in.
Hopefully all that is finished now (apart from this Wednesday afternoon) and I can get back to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next month (same as last time):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work on SHD (and have basic play possible)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create IPO prototype version 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decide which projects to pursue immediately, and which to put on pause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    

  </channel> 
</rss>
